Faculty of Education fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Special media records, 1975 - 1998; F-233-8; 14 contact sheets 105 photographs 545 slides 55 sound recordings 3 moving images; General note: photographs are located in sub-series 1, moving images in sub-series 2, sound recordings in sub-series 3.
  - Summer Institute on Teacher Education (SITE) lectures, 1983 - 1988; F-233-8-3; 39 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 41 audio cassettes.
    - SITE 1983: New Directions in Counselling and Education, F-233-8-3-1; 8 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 9 audio cassettes.
      The theme of the SITE 1983 was "New Directions in Counselling and Education". Speakers were Dr. David Aspy (Texas Women's University), Dr. Bernard Berenson (American International College), Dr. Lloyd West (University of Calgary), Dr. Jack Martin (SFU), and Dr. Bryan Hiebert (SFU). Records comprise audio cassettes.
      This sub-sub-series incorporates material formerly arranged by the Archives as RG-100/11/24.
      - David Aspy. The Use of Counselling Skills in Classroom Teaching: The Past and the Future, 12 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-1; General note: this is a tape made from a videotape of Dr. Aspy, who was unable to come to SFU. (Audio cassette OBJ-3942)
        Aspy, David; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/1, F-233-item10.
      - Bernard Berenson. An Introduction to Human Technology for Counsellors and Educators, 14 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3943, Audio cassette OBJ-3944)
        Berenson, Bernard; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/2, F-233-item11.
      - Lloyd West. Keeping the Guidance and Counselling Program Responsive to Interests and Desires of the Community, 19 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3945)
        West, Lloyd; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/3, F-233-item13.
      - Lloyd West. Renovating Guidance and Counselling: Agenda for the 80s, 21 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3946)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/4, F-233-item14.
      - David Aspy. Counselling and Teaching in a Productive Society, 26 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3947)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/5, F-233-item15.
      - Jack Martin. Curriculum Development and Instructional Counselling: New Strategies for School Counsellors, 28 July 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3948)
        Martin, Jack; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/6, F-233-item16.
      - Bernard Berenson. The Implications of Inclusive and Exclusive Systems for Human Resource Development, 2 August 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3949)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/7, F-233-item17.
      - Bryan Hiebert. Counselling Effectiveness: Towards Accountability, 4 August 1983; F-233-8-3-1-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3950)
        Hiebert, Bryan; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/8, F-233-item18.
    - SITE 1984: Computers in Education, F-233-8-3-2; 8 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 8 audio cassettes.
      The theme of SITE 1984 was "Computers in Education". Speakers were Daniel Watt, Nancy Flodin (British Columbia Teachers' Federation), Molly Watt, Seymour Papert, Gordon Lawrence (University of Florida), and Sandy Dawson (SFU). Records consist of audio cassettes.
      - Daniel Watt. Beyond Computer Literacy, 3 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3951)
        Watt, Daniel; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/9, F-233-item19.
        Informal access review completed on Feb. 16, 2022 (ML): no restricted information identified.
      - Nancy Flodin. The BC Scene: Computers in Education, 5 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3952)
        Flodin, Nancy; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/10, F-233-item20.
      - Molly Watt. Computer Based Learning Environments, 10 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3953)
        Watt, Molly; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/11, F-233-item21.
      - Seymour Papert. Stroing and Retrieving Information on a Microcomputer, 12 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3954)
        Papert, Seymour; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/12, F-233-item22.
      - Daniel Watt. The Computer as an Instrument for Creative Expression, 17 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3955)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/13, F-233-item23.
      - Gordon Lawrence. Learning Styles and Computers, 19 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3956)
        Lawrence, Gordon; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/14, F-233-item24.
      - Molly Watt. Looking at Software: The Story Behind the Scene, 24 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3957)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/15, F-233-item25.
      - Sandy Dawson. Beyond 1984: High-Tech / High-Touch, 26 July 1984; F-233-8-3-2-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3958)
        Dawson, A.J. (Sandy); Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/24/16, F-233-item26.
    - SITE 1985: Quality School Through Staff Development, F-233-8-3-3; 10 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 10 audio cassettes.
      The theme of SITE 1985 was "Quality School Through Staff Development". Speakers were Marv Wideen (SFU), Leo Marshall (North Vancouver School District), Linda Kaser (BC Ministry of Education), Kit Grauer (Richmond School District), Anna Steffin (Delta School District), Robert Stake (University of Illinois), Michael Fullan (Ontario Institute for Studies in Education), Walter Doyle (University of Texas), Maurice Gibbons (SFU), David Hopkins (West Glamorgan Institute of Higher Education), Lou Rubin (University of Illinois), Stan Shapson (SFU), and Ian Andrews (SFU). Records consist of audio cassettes.
      - Marvin Wideen. The Context of Staff Development, 2 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3959)
        Wideen, Marvin F.; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item27.
      - Leo Marshall, Linda Kaser, Kit Gauer, Anna Steffin. Issues in Staff Development in British Columbia, 4 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3960)
        Marshall, Leo; Kaser, Linda; Kit Gauer; Steffin, Anna; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item28.
      - Robert Stake. An Evolutionary View of Educational Improvement, 9 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3961)
        Stake, Robert; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item29.
      - Michael Fullen. Implementation of Staff Development Programs, 11 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3962)
        Michael Fullen; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item30.
      - Walter Doyle. Implications for Staff Development: School as a Workplace, 16 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3963)
        Doyle, Walter; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item31.
      - Walter Doyle. Research on Teaching as a Strategy for Staff Development, 18 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3964)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item32.
      - Maurice Gibbons. Self-Education as a Strategy for Staff Development, 23 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3965)
        Gibbons, Maurice; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item33.
      - David Hopkins. Teacher as Researcher: A Model for Staff Development, 25 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3966)
        Hopkins, David; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item34.
      - Lou Rubin. Implementation of Curricula and Staff Development, 30 July 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-3967)
        Rubin, Lou; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item35.
      - Stan Shapson, Ian Andrews. External Agencies and School Board Based Staff Development: Implications and Future Directions, 1 August 1985; F-233-8-3-3-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-3968)
        Shapson, Stanley M.; Andrews, Ian; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item36.
    - SITE 1987, F-233-8-3-4; 6 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 7 audio cassettes.
      Speakers at SITE 1987 were Tom Schroeder (University of Calgary), Robby Fried (Brown University), Wanda Cassidy (SFU), Milton McClaren (SFU), Robert Walker (SFU), and Kim Campbell (MLA). Records consist of audio cassettes.
      - Tom Schroeder. Understanding Understanding in Secondary School Mathematics, 9 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3969)
        Schroeder, Tom; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item37.
      - Robby Fried. Common Principles for an Uncommon Education, 14 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3970)
        Fried, Robby; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item38.
      - Wanda Cassidy. Practicing What We Preach in Social Studies Education, 21 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3971)
        Cassidy, Wanda; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item39.
      - M. McClaren. [No title], 23 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3894)
        McClaren, Milton; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item40.
      - Robert Walker. Music and Music Education for the Adolescent Mind, 28 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3895, Audio cassette OBJ-3896)
        Walker, Robert; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item41.
      - Kim Campbell. Secondary and Post-Secondary Education: Preparing for the 20th Century., 30 July 1987; F-233-8-3-4-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3897)
        Campbell, Kim; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item43.
    - SITE 1988: Global Issues, F-233-8-3-5; 7 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 7 audio cassettes.
      The theme of SITE 1988 was "Global Issues". Speakers recorded were Lucy McNeil (broadcaster), Robert Moore (Canadian International Development Agency), Milton McClaren (SFU), Fred Knelman, Stephen Owen, David Selby (University of York), and George McRobbie (University of Pennsylvania). Records consist of audio cassettes.
      - Lucy McNeil. The Impact of the Media on our Peception of the World, 11 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3898)
        McNeil, Lucy; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item44.
      - Robert Moore. Global Issues: World Economy and World Development, 13 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3899)
        Moore, Robert; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item45.
      - Milton McClaren. Global Issues: The Environment, 18 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3900)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item46.
      - Fred Knelman. The New Global Agenda: The 4th and 5th Worlds, 20 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3901)
        Knelman, Fred; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item47.
      - Stephen Owen. Global Issues: Conflict and Conflict Resolution, 25 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3902)
        Owen, Stephen; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item48.
      - David Selby. The Role of Schools in the Golden Age, 27 July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3903)
        Selby, David; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item49.
      - George McRobie. Global Issues: The Role of Technology, July 1988; F-233-8-3-5-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3904)
        McRobbie, George; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item50.
  - "The Future of Education Research" public lecture series audio recordings, 1985; F-233-8-4; 10 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 10 audio cassettes.
    Sub-series consists of audio recordings (cassettes) of a three-day public lecture series held by the Faculty of Education in July 1985, called "The Future of Education Research." Speakers were Robin Barrow (SFU), Jonas Soltis (Columbia University), Kieran Egan (SFU), Denis Phillips (Stanford University), LeRoy Daniels (University of British Columbia), and John Wilson (Oxford University). Records consist of audio cassettes.
    - Robin Barrow. The Future of Educational Research, 24 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3905, Audio cassette OBJ-3906)
      Barrow, Robin A.; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item51.
    - Jonas Soltis. The Persistence of Paradigms, 24 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3907, Audio cassette OBJ-3908)
      Jonas Soltis; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item53.
    - Kieran Egan. The Analytic and the Arbitrary in Educational Research, 24 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3909)
      Egan, Kieran; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item55.
    - Denis Phillips. Confounding the Grim Reaper, 25 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3910)
      Dennis Phillips; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item56.
    - LeRoy Daniels. What Psychology Can Do for Education, 25 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3911, Audio cassette OBJ-3912)
      LeRoy Daniels; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item57.
    - John Wilson. What Philosophy Can Do for Education, 26 July 1985; F-233-8-4-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3913, Audio cassette OBJ-3914)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-233-item59.
  - J.S. Woodsworth Summer Institute on Peace and War lecture series: audio recordings, 1986; F-233-8-5; 10 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 21 audio cassettes.
    Sub-series consists of audio recordings (cassettes) of a month-long series public lectures co-sponsored by the Faculty of Education and the Institute for the Humanities in July-Auguust 1986, called the J.S. Woodsworth Summer Instittute on Peace and War. Speakers were Dr. Ursula Franklin (University of Toronto), Dr. Magaret Benston (SFU), Dr. Martin Kitchen (SFU), Dr. David Barash, Dr. Neil Kyle, George Ignatieff (University of Toronto), Dr. Doug Ross (SFU), Dr. William Vanderburg (University of Toronto), and Joanna Miller (UNICEF Canada).
    For printed program, see series 7-1 "Faculty of Education publications", file 24.
    - Ursula Franklin. A Feminist Critique of Peace Research, 8 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3915, Audio cassette OBJ-3916)
      Franklin, Ursula; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/1, F-233-item61.
    - Margaret Benston. Science, Militarism and Masculinity, 10 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-3917, Audio cassette OBJ-3918)
      Benston, Maggie; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/2, F-233-item63.
    - Science for Peace, Science for War: Science, Peace and Conflict: A Symposium, 15 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-3919, Audio cassette OBJ-3920)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/3, F-233-item65.
    - Martin Kitchen. Historical Problems in Peace and War Studies, 17 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-3921, Audio cassette OBJ-3922)
      Kitchen, Martin; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/4, F-233-item67.
    - David Barash. The Psychology of the Arms Race, 22 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-3923, Audio cassette OBJ-3924)
      Barash, David; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/5, F-233-item69.
    - Neil Kyle. The Youth Culture of Despair: Children's Fears about Nuclear War, 24 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-3925, Audio cassette OBJ-3926)
      Kyle, Neil; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/6, F-233-item71.
    - George Ignatieff. Strategy for Survival, 29 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3927, Audio cassette OBJ-3928, Audio cassette OBJ-3929)
      Ignatieff, George; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/7, F-233-item73.
    - Douglas Ross. Geopolitical 'Culture' and the Future of the Arms Race, 31 July 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3930, Audio cassette OBJ-3931)
      Ross, Doug; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/8, F-233-item76.
    - William Vanderburg. Peace and War from a Cultural Perspective, 5 August 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-3932, Audio cassette OBJ-3933)
      Vanderburg, William; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/9, F-233-item78.
    - Joanna Miller. Concluding Symposium, 7 August 1986; F-233-8-5-0-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-3934, Audio cassette OBJ-3935)
      Miller, Joanna; Sound recordings
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/49/10, F-233-item80.